# 哈喽 雪鱼现在在银川
Hello, xueyu is at Yinchuan now
# 有句话叫做 吃在吴忠 游在银川
There is a saying that eats in Wuzhong and travel in Yinchuan
# 这次我专门来银川 耍一耍
I come to Yinchuan to travel for this time
# 在吴忠的时候 我吃了早茶 吃了羊杂
I eat Zaocha and mutton offal in Wuzhong while i was in Wuzhong
# 但是还有一种 手抓 没有尝到
But i haven’t tried Shouzhua yet
# 这次来银川呢 先把没有吃到手抓的遗憾弥补掉吧
This time I’m here to make up for my regret in Yinchuan
# 很多吴忠的手抓店 在银川这边也会有的
A lot shouzhuan restaurant from Wuzhong are open in Yinchuan
# 前一段时间 我刚在西宁这边吃过手抓羊排
A few weeks ago I just ate shouzhua lamb chops in Xining
# 不过同在西北
although it’s both in Northwest
# 宁夏的手抓和西宁的手抓还是有很大区别的
Shouzhua are different in Ningxia and Xining
# 这正好是遇上 羊肉刚出锅
Fresh cooked lamb just out of the pot
# 这个锅盖一打开
Once the lid open
# 羊肉的香味立刻飘过来冲击到脑子里
The fragment smell of lamb crashed my mind
# 大哥 我问一下 这里面主要是羊什么部位的肉
Brother, what part of lamb is the meat is?
# 主要是羊的前排 前羊排
Lamb front ribs mainly
# 这一锅大约能有多少斤
How many jin in a pot?
# 这一锅达到140斤
About 140 jin(70kg)
# 炖羊肉的汤里没有什么大料包
There is no seasoning package in the lamb soup
# 只有简单的葱姜这样的调味品
Just simple seasons like ginger and green onion
# 这么看着真的是 汤上面只是泛着一层清油
There is a layer of clear oil on the soup
# 仔细看看汤 汤还是很白的
The soup are white when you see it more serious
# 锅里是几乎不加盐的
There is no salt in the soup
# 炖的时候 羊汤的锅里几乎是不加盐的
They don’t add salt in the pot of soup when they boil the soup
# 这个锅里除了比较明显能够看到的羊排
We can see lamb ribs in the pot
# 还有一个不能不说
And we have to say
# 难以想象吧 它还是一种比较特色的美食
Hard to image, it is a special food
# 这一锅 羊脖子也就是四个到五个
There only four to five lamb neck in a pot
# 因为吃热制羊脖的很少 吃凉制的比较多
Because people more prefer to eat cold lamb neck
# 做羊脖的时间还比较长 它是最后才出锅
It also take very long time to make, lamb neck is the last to take out from the pot
# 这一个羊脖有三斤半
The lamb neck is about 3 jin and a half(1.75kg)
# 煮熟后也要剩余二斤半（缩水）
It still have 2 jin and a half(1.25kg) after cook(shrink)
# 师傅 这个羊脖大约需要煮多久
Master, how long time it take to cook the lamb neck?
# （开锅后）煮两个半小时
About 2 and a half hours(after boiling)
# （切羊脖）体现了刀工
It reflect the skill of cutting when they cut the lamb neck
# 纯手工剁制的 就为两片羊脖出来 薄如雪花
Hand chopped just for two slices of lamb neck, as thin as snowflake?
# 薄如雪花 都是手动剁出来的
As thin as snowflake, all by hand chopped
# 有些客人来说 你们这个羊脖是不是拿机子切的
Some customers will ask about is that chopped by machine
# 没有 全是师傅凭手工切出来的
No, all hand chopped by master
# 切好的羊脖 最后才能撒上椒盐 然后才能上桌
Chopped lamb neck are ready to serve after sprink salt and pepper on it
# 今天呢 点了一盘的凉羊脖 还有一盘的热的羊排
We ordered a cold lamb neck and a hot lamb ribs
# 这两盘肉都是码放好之后端上来的
The two plates of meat are ready to serve after tidy up
# 随着这两盘肉 一起上来的呢
Garlic and vinegar sauce are serve
# 还有一小碟的蒜醋汁
with the two plates of meat
# 还有一小碟的  吃肉不可缺少的大蒜
And a small plate of garlic, which are essential to eat with lam
# 这样好像才是西北吃肉的正确打开方式
This seems the right way to eat meat in northwest
# 它这个羊肉是原味的 只是在上桌之前先放了一点盐
This lamb are original flavor, just add some salt before serve
# 咱们呢 就是先尝尝
We just try how
# 什么都不蘸的这种羊肉是什么样的味道
The taste of original flavor of lamb without any seasoning
# 先来一个羊排吧
We try the lamb ribs first
# 试一试 手抓版
Try shouzhua
# 羊排是直接用手一抽 骨头就能掉下来
The bone of lamb ribs are easy to pull out from meat
# 炖的好软烂 看来是不能用手抓着吃了
It stewed very long time, looks we don’t need to use our hand
# 用筷子夹着吃
Eat it with our chopsticks
# 它这个羊排 就是这种肥瘦相间的 还冒着油
The lamb ribs are with fatty and lean meat, and the oil is coming out
# 羊排炖的很软烂
Lamb chops stewed very soft
# 我刚才就是用嘴唇吸溜进去的
I sucked it with my lips
# 宁夏人把肥的 叫做壮
Ningxia people called “fatty” to strong
# 我觉得这一盘 应该是死壮死壮（strong强壮）的吧
I think this plate is very ”strong”
# 是不是我的嘴上都是油
Look, is the oil all over my mouth?
# 你看 羊排都是带点肥油的
Look, all lamb ribs are with some fatty oil
# 它是热的 这么一吃 羊肉的香味特别足
It’s hot, so with very strong flavor and fragment of lamb
# 不得不说 这边的菜码真的是特别大
We have to say that they give large amount of meat for every plate
# 我看资料的时候 有句话是
There is a saying when I read the information
# 初级的吃货是喜欢吃手抓羊排的
Beginner foodies like to eat lamb chops
# 但是稍微高级一点 进阶一点喜欢吃的是凉的羊脖
And advanced foodie like to eat cold lamb neck
# 凉的羊脖 肥的就会明显少很多
Cold lamb neck with less fatty
# 看起来特别好看
Looks pretty good
# 像雪花一样
Like snowflake
# 羊脖：好细嫩
Lamb neck are soft and tender
# 忍不住再吃一口
Can not stop to eat
# 它这个是吃不出来什么调料的味道
I don’t know what seasonings they use  in the lamb neck
# 只能吃出来是这种稍微的咸味
Just taste some salty taste
# 还有羊肉的 这种带点肥的这种香味
And some fragment of lamb with fatty
# 掉了 掉了
dropped
# 蘸了蒜醋汁
With garlic and vinegar sauce dipping
# 好像把羊脖子上最后一点的油腻都掩盖了
It cover up oily taste of lamb neck
# 吃完了手抓 雪鱼即将前往的是镇北堡影视基地
After we finished eat, xueyu gonna go Zhenbeibao Film and Television Base
# 在这个地方你可以体验一下
We can experienced
# 至尊宝和紫霞仙子的爱情故事
Love story between zhizunbao and zixiaxianzi
# 前面还有比武招亲的吗 还是抛绣球的
Is there any contest in front of martial arts to recruit relatives? Or throwing hydrangea
# 小姐
Young lady
# 风流倜傥的
# 脚下生风的
# 腚大腰圆的
# 小姐
# 自己挑
# 自己选
# 小姐
请抛绣球
# 给你吧
Give it to you
# 刚才绣球直接到了我这里
# 我只是一个过客 没想到得到了一个小姐
# 来这里
拍照的经典动作
# 关  注
雪 鱼  探 店